# Ashraful Islam

Graduate Research Assistant at UAB aislam@uab.edu

github.com/ashraful-islam-rafi Java, C, C++, Python, Racket, PHP, JavaScript

#### Summary

Computer Science graduate student at the University of Alabama at Birmingham (UAB) with over 2 years of academic research experience and over 7 years of industry experience taking on roles such as Software Engineer, and Programmer.

# **EDUCATION**

# UNIVERSITY OF ALABAMA AT BIRMINGHAM

Birmingham, USA Jan 2022 - Present

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.) in Computer Science

o PI: Dr. Thomas Gilray, Assistant Professor, Department of Computer Science, UAB

#### LEADING UNIVERSITY

Sylhet, Bangladesh

B. Sc. in Computer Science and Engineering

Aug 2009 - Aug 2013

#### EXPERIENCE

| • UNIVERSITY OF A<br>Graduate Research Assist | ALABAMA AT BIRMINGHAM                    | Birmingham, USA<br>Jan 2022 - Present     |
|---|--|---|
| • BANGLA SEARCH Software Engineer (Resea      | ENGINE (PIPILIKA)  erch and Development) | Sylhet, Bangladesh<br>Aug 2017 - Mar 2021 |
| • SOUTHEAST UNIX Programmer                   | VERSITY                                  | Dhaka, Bangladesh<br>Apr 2015 - Aug 2017  |
| • IT LAB SOLUTION Software Developer          | IS LTD.                                  | Sylhet, Bangladesh<br>Sep 2013 - Dec 2014 |

### SKILLS

- Languages: Java, C, C++, Python, Racket, PHP, JavaScript
- Databases/Frameworks/Technologies: Spring Boot, Java Servlet, Flask, Codeigniter, Jsoup, Scrapy, jQuery, Bootstrap3, AJAX, MySQL, MongoDB, Apache Solr, HTML5, CSS3
- Others: Git, Docker, AWS, Maven, WordPress, SDLC, STLC, MVC, Agile, Scrum, Waterfall, Linux, Windows, MacOS

## Extracurricular / Activities

- Treasurer: Managed financial operations of the Bangladesh Student Association (BSA), a graduate student organization at UAB
- Judge: Served as a judge of the Summer 2023 Undergraduate Research Expo, UAB
- Tutor: Conducted over 15 programming workshops focused on Data Structures and Algorithms at Leading University, with each session attended by more than 40 students.
- Contest Participation: Competed in various national and inter-university programming contests, including IUT 4th National ICT Fest (2012), NSU ACM ICPC Dhaka Site (2011), SUST Inter-University Programming Contest (2011), and IUT Inter-University Programming Contest (2011)
- Public Relation Officer: Coordinated and managed 3 Intra-university programming contests for the Leading University Computer Club (LUCC)